<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-01T10:49:02+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Lit Blog</title><subtitle>Even I cannot understand why this exists</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Dark Season 1</title><link href="/dark-season-one/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Season 1" /><published>2020-10-07T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-07T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/dark-season-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="/dark-season-one/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;dark-season-1--explained&quot;&gt;DARK Season 1 : Explained&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-family-tree&quot;&gt;The family tree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/dark-s1/dark-family-tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;family&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start&quot;&gt;Start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series begins in &lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt; with Michael Kahnwald, father of Jonas, husband of Hannah hanging himself and leaving behind a note saying ‘not to be opened until 4 November at 10:13pm’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut to November 4, when we learn that a red-haired boy called Erik Obendorf has been missing for two weeks and the case is assigned to police officer Ulrich – the case is very personal to him because his teenage brother went missing in Winden 33 years ago and has never been found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 4th, Ulrich’s son Mikkel goes missing in the woods near the caves, then the next day a dead kid turns up in the woods wearing ’80s togs and a nickel with ‘1986’ on it round his neck. He’s carrying a Walkman and he has severe burns around his eyes and his eardrums are completely burst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teenager Jonas was with Mikkel on the night of his disappearance and resolves to try to find him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we see Mikkel emerge from the cave in the woods where he went missing. Only when he gets back into the town he realises it’s not 2019, in fact it’s 1986.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the basic setup of a show focused on time-travel between three eras: 1953, 1986 and 2019. The action is entirely set around Winden and is focused on four families – the Kahnwalds, the Nielsens, the Dopplers and the Tiedmanns, who have lived in the town for generations (which is convenient since characters regularly encounter younger versions of themselves and their relatives when they time-travel via the cave).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, it gets complicated. Here’s what we think is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-travel&quot;&gt;Time Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This centres around an underground cellar where Noah (more on him later) has built a machine which opens wormholes in 33-year increments (it’s 33 years because of a theory that because a year isn’t actually exactly 365 days it’s only every 33 years where things are completely aligned and ‘reset’ – apparently).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The missing kids are being used to test the time machine, which currently doesn’t work properly and just kills them and dumps them back in the cellar in another era. At the same time it opens a wormhole in the caves so Helge (more on him later too) can go through, find the bodies and move them out of the cellar to be found. The boy found in episode one is Mads, brother of Ulrich, who went missing as a teenager in 1986 and turns up in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-stranger&quot;&gt;The Stranger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn that the stranger is in fact Jonas Kahnwald as an adult. The Stranger is a time-traveller who wants to destroy the time loop and plans to do this with the help of a machine built by clockmaker and time-travel expert Tannhaus. Noah claims that it’s The Stranger’s attempt to close the loop that actually created it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;noah&quot;&gt;Noah&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noah is a murderous time-travelling priest, and he’s at war with Claudia (more later) to control time travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of season one Noah’s origins are still unclear, though there are clues. While most of the other characters we meet at different ages, we only ever see Noah as a middle-aged man – or at least we think so. His priest’s get-up is a massive advantage since his clothing doesn’t tie him to one era in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s an implication that Noah could be the estranged husband of Agnes Nielsen and the father of Tronte – Tronte has cigar burns on his arms which seem to have been inflicted by his father. His mother Agnes says she was married to a priest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1953, the farmer who has had 33 of his sheep turn up dead one day also says: “There’s a new priest at the church”. Agnes and Tronte are new in town (and rent a room from Claudia’s mother).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;claudia&quot;&gt;Claudia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claudia is an expert time-traveller – and at war with Noah to control time travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1986, Claudia is the head of the nuclear power plant that’s at the centre of Winden. She learns that there’s been a radioactive leak over the summer. Barrels of nuclear waste are stored in the caves – these chemicals are stolen by The Stranger and power the device made by Tannhaus which he uses to destroy/create the time loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claudia’s dog goes missing in 1953 through the caves and turns up again in 1986 where Claudia finds her. Claudia is aware of time travel (and in 1986 is given Tannhaus’ book &lt;em&gt;A Journey Through Time&lt;/em&gt; by Helge) and seems to be the main opposition to Noah. Or is she? We’re really not clear if she’s a goodie or a baddie by the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s Claudia who gives the blueprints of the device to Tannhaus and convinces The Stranger to fix it so that he can destroy the time loop. Noah says she lied to The Stranger – but it’s not like he’s terribly trustworthy anyway. There is a sense that the two sides we might follow in season two are Helge and Noah vs Jonas (The Stranger) and Claudia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;helge&quot;&gt;Helge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helge is the father of Peter and the father-in-law of Charlotte. He’s also the owner of the time-travel cellar (in 2019 and 1986 certainly). Helge is a pawn of Noah, and works with him to abduct and then later cover up the killings of the children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helge’s time line is super complicated….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helge is a child in 1953. Ulrich from 2019 goes back in time and meets the young Helge and tries to kill him by hitting him in the head with a rock and dumping him in the time-travel cellar. But Helge isn’t dead. When adult Jonas sets off the machine built by clockmaker and time-travel expert Tannhaus (as ever, more on him later) with the intention of closing the wormhole, instead it creates it, linking teenage Jonas and child-Helge who are both in the time-travel cellar – Helge in 1953, Jonas in 1986.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They reach out for each other and in doing so, Jonas is catapulted into the future (presumably 2052). It’s not clear exactly what happens to Helge at this point, but we’d imagine this is the point at which Noah would have gone to recruit him – this is borne out by Helge’s son Peter, who says his father was kidnapped as a child in 1953.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile in 2019, we also learn from Peter that Helge had an accident in November 1986. Old Helge in 2019 has dementia, but begins to have several attacks of conscience (partly brought on by Ulrich’s realisation that Helge was responsible for the killings). Old Helge claims he can fix things and change the past and the future, and he leaves the care facility where he lives to go back in time to 1986.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There, he attempts to talk middle-aged Helge out of working with Noah. But middle-aged Helge won’t listen to his older self and instead goes back to Noah, prompting Old Helge to try to kill him in a car crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old Helge only succeeds in killing his older self and injuring middle-aged Helge, who consequently misses the scheduled interview he was supposed to have with the police. An interview which might possibly have led the police to realise he was involved in the child disappearances and could have stopped the whole thing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;causality&quot;&gt;Causality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout &lt;em&gt;Dark&lt;/em&gt; there are paradoxes, such as the above, where someone time-travelling actually ends up being the cause of the thing they’d travelled back in time to prevent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stranger creates the time loop by trying to destroy it. He’s only able to do so with the machine built by Tannhaus, but Tannhaus only knows how to complete his machine because The Stranger brings him a completed (but broken) version back from the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noah has a book which seems to chart all of the events before they’ve even happened (certainly up to 2019) which implies he might be from a future further on – possibly 2052 – or just an expert time-traveller who has studied the events of the different eras. This also implies that there’s an element of the idea of Fate here – that everything was always going to be exactly as it is and it’s impossible to change the past or the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;peter&quot;&gt;Peter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter is Helge’s son and the husband of Charlotte who’s a policewoman working with Ulrich. Peter is gay and occasionally visits a transvestite male prostitute. He’s roped into the time-travel thing in 2019 when he’s in the cellar (which belongs to Helge) doing the ‘Serenity Prayer’ on the night of Mikkel’s disappearance when the body of Mads (Ulrich’s brother who disappeared in 1986) suddenly drops through the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He calls Tronte (Mads’ father) who turns up with Claudia, who says they must take the body to where it will be found. It’s likely therefore that he is clued-in to the time-travel thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mikkel-and-jonas&quot;&gt;Mikkel and Jonas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mikkel is revealed to be Jonas’ father – aka Michael (who kills himself in the prologue and leaves the note with instructions not to read it until Mikkel has already travelled back in time). Mikkel travels back to 1986 and is unable to get back to his own time. Dejected and on his own, he’s eventually taken to hospital where he meets nurse Ines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They form a bond and when it’s time for him to be discharged, Ines takes Mikkel in instead. Mikkel tells Ines he’s from the future, though she doesn’t necessarily believe him initially. Later though, she realises (because Mikkel is born and grows up in Winden to become the boy she first met, before he disappears) but doesn’t try to prevent his disappearing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martha, Mikkel’s sister and Jonas’ love interest, is in fact Jonas’ aunt – which he realises and therefore rejects her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bartosz&quot;&gt;Bartosz&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was a friend of Jonas in 2019 but because he finds out that Jonas got together with Martha (before he knew she was his aunt) even though she was Bartosz’s girlfriend, he turns against Jonas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bartosz is contacted by Noah who makes various predictions about things that will happen via his special book – all of which he gets correct – and manages to convince Bartosz to trust him. Bartosz is therefore likely to join TEAM NOAH. Claudia is actually Bartosz’ grandmother – however, his parents told him she was dead so they’re very much estranged. Some people on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/DarK/comments/7gwev1/episode_discussion_s01e10_alpha_and_omega/&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; reckon that Noah might actually BE Bartosz. We’re not sure, but it’s plausible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aleksander-and-regina&quot;&gt;Aleksander and Regina&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aleksander is a young man who helps out young Regina (Claudia’s daughter) in 1986. Regina asks her mother if she’ll give Aleks a job at the power plant and Claudia eventually does, though it’s a top secret job in the cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aleks has actually assumed the identity of another man. His real name is Boris Niewman – we see him burying two passports (his own and that of the real Aleksandr Köhler) along with a gun, in the forest. Young Hannah sees him do this in 1986. In 2019, she uses this information to blackmail him so he’ll “ruin Ulrich’s life” after Ulrich ends their affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the finale, Jonas is in some sort of dystopian future. He finds himself in a cabin with pictures of past, present and future version of the townsfolk pinned to the wall with articles and links joining them. As he ventures outside, he is hit in the head with the butt of a gun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you go, crystal clear.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>karthik</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="recap" /><category term="series" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">DARK Season 1 : Explained The family tree Start The series begins in 2019 with Michael Kahnwald, father of Jonas, husband of Hannah hanging himself and leaving behind a note saying ‘not to be opened until 4 November at 10:13pm’. Cut to November 4, when we learn that a red-haired boy called Erik Obendorf has been missing for two weeks and the case is assigned to police officer Ulrich – the case is very personal to him because his teenage brother went missing in Winden 33 years ago and has never been found. On the 4th, Ulrich’s son Mikkel goes missing in the woods near the caves, then the next day a dead kid turns up in the woods wearing ’80s togs and a nickel with ‘1986’ on it round his neck. He’s carrying a Walkman and he has severe burns around his eyes and his eardrums are completely burst. Teenager Jonas was with Mikkel on the night of his disappearance and resolves to try to find him. The next morning we see Mikkel emerge from the cave in the woods where he went missing. Only when he gets back into the town he realises it’s not 2019, in fact it’s 1986. That’s the basic setup of a show focused on time-travel between three eras: 1953, 1986 and 2019. The action is entirely set around Winden and is focused on four families – the Kahnwalds, the Nielsens, the Dopplers and the Tiedmanns, who have lived in the town for generations (which is convenient since characters regularly encounter younger versions of themselves and their relatives when they time-travel via the cave). Unsurprisingly, it gets complicated. Here’s what we think is going on. Time Travel This centres around an underground cellar where Noah (more on him later) has built a machine which opens wormholes in 33-year increments (it’s 33 years because of a theory that because a year isn’t actually exactly 365 days it’s only every 33 years where things are completely aligned and ‘reset’ – apparently). The missing kids are being used to test the time machine, which currently doesn’t work properly and just kills them and dumps them back in the cellar in another era. At the same time it opens a wormhole in the caves so Helge (more on him later too) can go through, find the bodies and move them out of the cellar to be found. The boy found in episode one is Mads, brother of Ulrich, who went missing as a teenager in 1986 and turns up in 2019. The Stranger We learn that the stranger is in fact Jonas Kahnwald as an adult. The Stranger is a time-traveller who wants to destroy the time loop and plans to do this with the help of a machine built by clockmaker and time-travel expert Tannhaus. Noah claims that it’s The Stranger’s attempt to close the loop that actually created it in the first place. Noah Noah is a murderous time-travelling priest, and he’s at war with Claudia (more later) to control time travel. At the end of season one Noah’s origins are still unclear, though there are clues. While most of the other characters we meet at different ages, we only ever see Noah as a middle-aged man – or at least we think so. His priest’s get-up is a massive advantage since his clothing doesn’t tie him to one era in particular. There’s an implication that Noah could be the estranged husband of Agnes Nielsen and the father of Tronte – Tronte has cigar burns on his arms which seem to have been inflicted by his father. His mother Agnes says she was married to a priest. In 1953, the farmer who has had 33 of his sheep turn up dead one day also says: “There’s a new priest at the church”. Agnes and Tronte are new in town (and rent a room from Claudia’s mother). Claudia Claudia is an expert time-traveller – and at war with Noah to control time travel. In 1986, Claudia is the head of the nuclear power plant that’s at the centre of Winden. She learns that there’s been a radioactive leak over the summer. Barrels of nuclear waste are stored in the caves – these chemicals are stolen by The Stranger and power the device made by Tannhaus which he uses to destroy/create the time loop. Claudia’s dog goes missing in 1953 through the caves and turns up again in 1986 where Claudia finds her. Claudia is aware of time travel (and in 1986 is given Tannhaus’ book A Journey Through Time by Helge) and seems to be the main opposition to Noah. Or is she? We’re really not clear if she’s a goodie or a baddie by the end. It’s Claudia who gives the blueprints of the device to Tannhaus and convinces The Stranger to fix it so that he can destroy the time loop. Noah says she lied to The Stranger – but it’s not like he’s terribly trustworthy anyway. There is a sense that the two sides we might follow in season two are Helge and Noah vs Jonas (The Stranger) and Claudia. Helge Helge is the father of Peter and the father-in-law of Charlotte. He’s also the owner of the time-travel cellar (in 2019 and 1986 certainly). Helge is a pawn of Noah, and works with him to abduct and then later cover up the killings of the children. Helge’s time line is super complicated…. Helge is a child in 1953. Ulrich from 2019 goes back in time and meets the young Helge and tries to kill him by hitting him in the head with a rock and dumping him in the time-travel cellar. But Helge isn’t dead. When adult Jonas sets off the machine built by clockmaker and time-travel expert Tannhaus (as ever, more on him later) with the intention of closing the wormhole, instead it creates it, linking teenage Jonas and child-Helge who are both in the time-travel cellar – Helge in 1953, Jonas in 1986. They reach out for each other and in doing so, Jonas is catapulted into the future (presumably 2052). It’s not clear exactly what happens to Helge at this point, but we’d imagine this is the point at which Noah would have gone to recruit him – this is borne out by Helge’s son Peter, who says his father was kidnapped as a child in 1953. Meanwhile in 2019, we also learn from Peter that Helge had an accident in November 1986. Old Helge in 2019 has dementia, but begins to have several attacks of conscience (partly brought on by Ulrich’s realisation that Helge was responsible for the killings). Old Helge claims he can fix things and change the past and the future, and he leaves the care facility where he lives to go back in time to 1986. There, he attempts to talk middle-aged Helge out of working with Noah. But middle-aged Helge won’t listen to his older self and instead goes back to Noah, prompting Old Helge to try to kill him in a car crash. Old Helge only succeeds in killing his older self and injuring middle-aged Helge, who consequently misses the scheduled interview he was supposed to have with the police. An interview which might possibly have led the police to realise he was involved in the child disappearances and could have stopped the whole thing… Causality Throughout Dark there are paradoxes, such as the above, where someone time-travelling actually ends up being the cause of the thing they’d travelled back in time to prevent. The Stranger creates the time loop by trying to destroy it. He’s only able to do so with the machine built by Tannhaus, but Tannhaus only knows how to complete his machine because The Stranger brings him a completed (but broken) version back from the future. Noah has a book which seems to chart all of the events before they’ve even happened (certainly up to 2019) which implies he might be from a future further on – possibly 2052 – or just an expert time-traveller who has studied the events of the different eras. This also implies that there’s an element of the idea of Fate here – that everything was always going to be exactly as it is and it’s impossible to change the past or the future. Peter Peter is Helge’s son and the husband of Charlotte who’s a policewoman working with Ulrich. Peter is gay and occasionally visits a transvestite male prostitute. He’s roped into the time-travel thing in 2019 when he’s in the cellar (which belongs to Helge) doing the ‘Serenity Prayer’ on the night of Mikkel’s disappearance when the body of Mads (Ulrich’s brother who disappeared in 1986) suddenly drops through the ceiling. He calls Tronte (Mads’ father) who turns up with Claudia, who says they must take the body to where it will be found. It’s likely therefore that he is clued-in to the time-travel thing. Mikkel and Jonas Mikkel is revealed to be Jonas’ father – aka Michael (who kills himself in the prologue and leaves the note with instructions not to read it until Mikkel has already travelled back in time). Mikkel travels back to 1986 and is unable to get back to his own time. Dejected and on his own, he’s eventually taken to hospital where he meets nurse Ines. They form a bond and when it’s time for him to be discharged, Ines takes Mikkel in instead. Mikkel tells Ines he’s from the future, though she doesn’t necessarily believe him initially. Later though, she realises (because Mikkel is born and grows up in Winden to become the boy she first met, before he disappears) but doesn’t try to prevent his disappearing again. Martha, Mikkel’s sister and Jonas’ love interest, is in fact Jonas’ aunt – which he realises and therefore rejects her. Bartosz He was a friend of Jonas in 2019 but because he finds out that Jonas got together with Martha (before he knew she was his aunt) even though she was Bartosz’s girlfriend, he turns against Jonas. Bartosz is contacted by Noah who makes various predictions about things that will happen via his special book – all of which he gets correct – and manages to convince Bartosz to trust him. Bartosz is therefore likely to join TEAM NOAH. Claudia is actually Bartosz’ grandmother – however, his parents told him she was dead so they’re very much estranged. Some people on Reddit reckon that Noah might actually BE Bartosz. We’re not sure, but it’s plausible. Aleksander and Regina Aleksander is a young man who helps out young Regina (Claudia’s daughter) in 1986. Regina asks her mother if she’ll give Aleks a job at the power plant and Claudia eventually does, though it’s a top secret job in the cave. Aleks has actually assumed the identity of another man. His real name is Boris Niewman – we see him burying two passports (his own and that of the real Aleksandr Köhler) along with a gun, in the forest. Young Hannah sees him do this in 1986. In 2019, she uses this information to blackmail him so he’ll “ruin Ulrich’s life” after Ulrich ends their affair. The future At the end of the finale, Jonas is in some sort of dystopian future. He finds himself in a cabin with pictures of past, present and future version of the townsfolk pinned to the wall with articles and links joining them. As he ventures outside, he is hit in the head with the butt of a gun. So there you go, crystal clear.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/posts/dark-s1/poster.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/posts/dark-s1/poster.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I made this ?</title><link href="/Why-I-made-this/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I made this ?" /><published>2020-10-03T15:34:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-03T15:34:00+00:00</updated><id>/Why-I-made-this</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Why-I-made-this/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-i-made-this&quot;&gt;Why I Made This&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, seriously. This was the best title I could think (at that time anyway)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the main reason was that I needed something to kill time and occupy
myself with, which is really stupid considering I plan to crack India’s most
craziest exam after school. If you really have nothing else to do and/or am as
bored as I am feel free to read my previous post, in which I rant about all of
this (in part at least)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess I am stupid after all&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;effort-undertaken&quot;&gt;Effort undertaken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really am quite happy with how this thing looks, took quite some time to set
it up to my personal liking, but I would say the satisfaction it gave me, but
then again, I easily get bored with really anything and this will probably keep
me occupied for a week tops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I didn’t had to go to much trouble to set all of this up, but again
that’s also because I like to do this. Aaahhh idk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-i-change-the-look-every-so-often&quot;&gt;Why do I change the look every so often&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tl;dr : I get bored&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;did-i-abandon-this&quot;&gt;Did I abandon this&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is here for two reasons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I wanted this post to be longer&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I wanted to tell the people who are reading this (yeah I am optimistic too)
if I had abandoned this&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;So if the build status image, shows passing, this is still alive. If not then
idk
&lt;img src=&quot;https://api.travis-ci.com/dopewind/dopewind.github.io.svg?branch=master&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>karthik</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Why I Made This</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/posts/Why-I-made-this/why.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/posts/Why-I-made-this/why.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2020 Thoughts</title><link href="/2020-Thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2020 Thoughts" /><published>2020-09-19T14:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-19T14:40:00+00:00</updated><id>/2020-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020-Thoughts/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;2020-so-far&quot;&gt;2020 so far&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, I’d say life has been great so far in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now don’t get me wrong. I don’t want a global pandemic to destroy the world or anything, but the thing is I love the quarantine life. Now that I type this out, I guess this makes we an introvert (whatever)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-race&quot;&gt;The Race&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Grade 12 Indian student, I gotta say this upfront, life kinda sucks (sometimes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again a disclaimer here – I am very very privileged to be born into a financially stable and nice family, and &lt;em&gt;I am grateful&lt;/em&gt; for it. Now, if you’re an Indian you’ll understand where I am going with this, if you don’t understand at this point congratulations, you never had to experience it. Stay with me, I’m gonna break it down for you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-expectation&quot;&gt;The Expectation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll get straight to it, you expect an Asian kid to perform well in their academics (not being racist here), so you’ll probably don’t need to tell us about our own folk. Almost every Indian parent (of the current parent generation) expects their kid to be smart and intelligent (and mind you, most parents’ idea of ‘smart’ are not the regular smart) and I don’t blame them for it. I am actually grateful that I’m a Gen Z because the millennial kids had this in a way worse-r form . The moment a child is born the father labels him a Doctor or an Engineer (notice I wrote ‘him’ and not them) and when the kid doesn’t live up to his ‘reputation’ he is declared wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what I’m gonna stop it at this, if you’re really interested, checkout the hugely viral Quora post which will give you an almost perfect idea in what I’m talking about –&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Which-coaching-institute-is-best-for-my-kid-in-5th-standard-for-IIT-JEE-preparation&quot;&gt;Read the full thing to get the true idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m gonna stop my rant here as I feel so good about myself after throwing all my thoughts for the Internet to read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✌&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. I am not done with my rant, I’ll be back&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>karthik</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="rant" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">2020 so far In a nutshell, I’d say life has been great so far in 2020. Now don’t get me wrong. I don’t want a global pandemic to destroy the world or anything, but the thing is I love the quarantine life. Now that I type this out, I guess this makes we an introvert (whatever) The Race As a Grade 12 Indian student, I gotta say this upfront, life kinda sucks (sometimes). Again a disclaimer here – I am very very privileged to be born into a financially stable and nice family, and I am grateful for it. Now, if you’re an Indian you’ll understand where I am going with this, if you don’t understand at this point congratulations, you never had to experience it. Stay with me, I’m gonna break it down for you The Expectation I’ll get straight to it, you expect an Asian kid to perform well in their academics (not being racist here), so you’ll probably don’t need to tell us about our own folk. Almost every Indian parent (of the current parent generation) expects their kid to be smart and intelligent (and mind you, most parents’ idea of ‘smart’ are not the regular smart) and I don’t blame them for it. I am actually grateful that I’m a Gen Z because the millennial kids had this in a way worse-r form . The moment a child is born the father labels him a Doctor or an Engineer (notice I wrote ‘him’ and not them) and when the kid doesn’t live up to his ‘reputation’ he is declared wasted. You know what I’m gonna stop it at this, if you’re really interested, checkout the hugely viral Quora post which will give you an almost perfect idea in what I’m talking about –&amp;gt; Read the full thing to get the true idea I think I’m gonna stop my rant here as I feel so good about myself after throwing all my thoughts for the Internet to read ✌ PS. I am not done with my rant, I’ll be back</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/posts/2020%20Thoughts/covid-wash.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/posts/2020%20Thoughts/covid-wash.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">First Words</title><link href="/first-words/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Words" /><published>2020-09-17T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T10:20:00+00:00</updated><id>/first-words</id><content type="html" xml:base="/first-words/">&lt;p&gt;Hey there&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess these are my first words. Oh wait! I’ve already said them. Damn it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah you’re gonna see that completely non existent attempt at humor more often than you’d expect ( was that an attempted joke? )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway I know most of you guys stumbled here from some random Google search or some reddit mention or something ( or whatever ig. ) and don’t give two cents for what I write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if you’re still here after all that ( you read all that crap? ), you’re just in for the ride, whether it be my tech adventures or just my musings on life ( I know I’m probably mad )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karthik Vinayan&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>karthik</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="welcome" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">Hey there</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/posts/Initial%20Thoughts/think.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/posts/Initial%20Thoughts/think.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>